export const final_mdsp_coaching_phase_1 = [
  {
    choices: ["tolerance", "crest", "clearance", "lead"],
    correctAnswer: "clearance",
    question: "It is the radial distance between the top of the tooth and the bottoms of the mating tooth space.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["lead float file", "vixen file", "A and C", "mile file"],
    correctAnswer: "A and C",
    question: "For filling lead or babbit, use a",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["dull yellow sparks", "no sparks", "red sparsk", "bright shiny sparks"],
    correctAnswer: "dull yellow sparks",
    question: "A piece of cast iron hold against an emery wheel will give off",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["at an angle of 60Â° at the center", "at the right angle of the cutter", "against the milling cutter", "the direction of the cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "against the milling cutter",
    question: "In up cut milling, the work piece is fed",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["low temperature welding", "applying flux during welding process", "cleaning the welded surface after the welding operation is over", "connecting load pipes by soldering alloy"],
    correctAnswer: "connecting load pipes by soldering alloy",
    question: "Wiping is the process of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["cutting gears in a milling", "fixing job out angle in a grinder", "cutting tapers in a lathe", "cutting gears in a shaper"],
    correctAnswer: "cutting gears in a shaper",
    question: "Angle plate is used for ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["large and small", "single-cut and double-cut", "flat shapes and round shapes", "rough and smooth"],
    correctAnswer: "single-cut and double-cut",
    question: "Files are divided into two general classes, namely                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["distortion", "shrinkage", "machining", "easy withdrawal"],
    correctAnswer: "easy withdrawal",
    question: "Rapping allowance is provided on a pattern take care of ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["boring", "drilling", "reaming", "center-drilling"],
    correctAnswer: "center-drilling",
    question: "On a lathe, the dead center is used after",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["no side rake", "less side rake", "more top rake", "more side rake"],
    correctAnswer: "less side rake",
    question: "When material in a lathe, the harder the material being cut, the tool bit should have",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["in flow", "smooth flow", "out flow", "solidification of molten material"],
    correctAnswer: "in flow",
    question: "Sprue is passage provided for the",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Planer", "Power saw", "Tool grinder", "Shaper"],
    correctAnswer: "Power saw",
    question: "A machine tool used to cut metals a lift, medium and large section using a reciprocating hacksaw blade.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["mm", "mm per degree", "rpm", "mm per revolution"],
    correctAnswer: "mm per revolution",
    question: "Feed in the lathe machine is expressed in",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["external diameter", "design", "tubular", "inside diameter"],
    correctAnswer: "inside diameter",
    question: "The size of all the pipes from 1/16 inches to 12 inches is defined by _______ size.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["interference of metals", "negative fits", "negative allowance", "negative allowance"],
    correctAnswer: "interference of metals",
    question: "When hole is smaller than the shaft, it will take pressure to pull the parts together, and the allowance is negative and is termed as:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Feed the casting at a rate consistent with the rate of solidification", "Feed molten metal from pouring basin to gas", "Act as a reservoir for molten metal", "Help feed the casting until oil solidification takes place"],
    correctAnswer: "Help feed the casting until oil solidification takes place",
    question: "What is the purpose of risers?",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["shiny", "harder", "medium hard", "softer"],
    correctAnswer: "softer",
    question: "The purpose of annealing is to make a metal:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Groove", "Flute", "Trap", "Lap"],
    correctAnswer: "Trap",
    question: "A cylindrical bar of steel with threads formed around it and grooves or flutes running lengthwise in it, intersecting with threads to form cutting edges. It is used to cut internal threads.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["tack weld", "oxy-acetylene weld", "fusion weld", "electric weld"],
    correctAnswer: "tack weld",
    question: "A weld made to hold the parts of a weldmet in proper alignment until final welds are made.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["wahl&amp;amp;#39;s factor", "spring scale", "spring index", "spring rate"],
    correctAnswer: "spring index",
    question: "Ratio of coil to wire diameter, a measure of coil curvature.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["any of the above ", "cold rolled steel", "structural steel", "hot rolled steel"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above ",
    question: "A hacksaw blade with 14 TPI is best suited for cutting                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["module", "lead", "crest", "clearance"],
    correctAnswer: "lead",
    question: "The distance a helical gear would thread along its axis one revolution of it were free to move axially.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["without oiling", "that is dirty", "without a handle", "with a tang"],
    correctAnswer: "with a tang",
    question: "Never use a file",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["planer", "grinder", "shaper", "power saw"],
    correctAnswer: "grinder",
    question: "A machine used in shaping metal by means of abrasive wheel or removal of metals with abrasive.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["knurling", "counter sinking", "performing", "squaring"],
    correctAnswer: "counter sinking",
    question: "The operation of making a cone-shaped enlargement of the end of a hole, as for a recess for a flat head screw.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Turning", "Notching", "Piercing", "Reaming"],
    correctAnswer: "Reaming",
    question: "It is an operation of sizing and finishing a hole by means of a cutting tool having several cutting edges.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["jewelry file", "square file", "knife file", "mill file"],
    correctAnswer: "knife file",
    question: "The best file to use when finishing sharp corner or a lots of grooves is the",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["vernier caliper", "slip gage", "micrometer", "angle gage"],
    correctAnswer: "angle gage",
    question: "A sine bar cannot be used without a/an",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Shaping", "Laying out", "Shapping", "Hobbing"],
    correctAnswer: "Laying out",
    question: "The hop term used to include the marking or inscribing of center points circle area of straight lines upon metal surface either curve or flat, for the guidance of the worker called:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["sheet metal over 18 gauges", "brass and copper", "any of the above", "tubing"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "Hacksaw blade with 24 TPI is best suited for cutting                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["use a blade with fewer teeth per inch", "set the blade in the frame with the teeth facing toward you", "turn the blade at right angles to the frame", "turn the blade upside down in the frame"],
    correctAnswer: "turn the blade at right angles to the frame",
    question: "When cutting a long thin piece of metal",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["too much rake angle", "too much high speed", "not enough speed", "B or C"],
    correctAnswer: "B or C",
    question: "When the outer corners of the cutting edges of a drill wear away to rapidly, it is an indication of?",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["grinder", "shaper", "lathe", "drilling machine"],
    correctAnswer: "shaper",
    question: "Quick return mechanism is used in a ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["hot forging", "foundry", "fitting", "cold forging"],
    correctAnswer: "hot forging",
    question: "A vent wire is used in ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["brass", "tool steel", "cast iron", "any of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "All hard hacksaw blade is best suited for work on                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["type of teeth", "all of the above", "size", "shape"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "Which of the following information is necessary when ordering a file",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["glove hand", "pliers", "a vise and a clamp", "the hand"],
    correctAnswer: "a vise and a clamp",
    question: "When using a drill press, the work should be hold with:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["10 to 20", "14 to 28", "16 to 32", "18 to 24"],
    correctAnswer: "18 to 24",
    question: "It is recommended for high speed application that the maximum number of teeth in small sprocket should be:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["double-cut fine-tooth file", "crossing file", "mill file", "single-cut fine-tooth file"],
    correctAnswer: "single-cut fine-tooth file",
    question: "For finishing a piece of work to size the file to use is the",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["cutting tools", "drill bits", "hollow work pieces", "face plate"],
    correctAnswer: "hollow work pieces",
    question: "Mandrel used to hold",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["seals", "gaskets", "packings", "felts"],
    correctAnswer: "packings",
    question: "To prevent leakage in dynamic seals, it is recommended to use",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["base helix angle", "pressure angle", "approach angle", "recess angle"],
    correctAnswer: "pressure angle",
    question: "The angle developed between tooth profile and radial line at its pitch point is referred as:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["all of the above", "prevent the blade from loose temper", "prevent the blade from overheating", "absorb heat of friction"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "A coolant is used when cutting a material in a power hacksaw to",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["backlash", "arc of approach", "arc of recess", "arc of action"],
    correctAnswer: "arc of recess",
    question: "An arc of the pitch circle through which a tooth travels from its contact to a mating tooth at the pitch point to the point where contact ceases.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["collect chuck", "four jaw self centering chuck", "three jaw chuck", "magnetic chuck"],
    correctAnswer: "three jaw chuck",
    question: "Chuck use in turret lathe is",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Tool grinder", "Planer", "Lathe machine", "Broaching machine"],
    correctAnswer: "Tool grinder",
    question: "A machine tool in which an abrasive wheel is used as a cutting tool to obtain a very smooth finish.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["planer", "grinder", "lathe", "slotter"],
    correctAnswer: "slotter",
    question: "A machine tool which is very similar to a shaper except that the ram reciprocates vertically rather than horizontally.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["chord length", "chordal thickness", "chord space", "chord clearance"],
    correctAnswer: "chordal thickness",
    question: "Tooth width measured along the chord at the pitch circle.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Turning", "Forging", "Rolling", "Casting"],
    correctAnswer: "Rolling",
    question: "The process of forming metals by the use of dies after the metal is heated to its plastic range.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["60 m/min", "30 m/min", "40 m/min", "50 m/min"],
    correctAnswer: "40 m/min",
    question: "Which of the following is the cutting speed m of brass?",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["four position", "one position", "three position", "two position"],
    correctAnswer: "four position",
    question: "A hacksaw blade can be placed in a frame in",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["middle portion of the mold", "bottom half of molding box", "coating on the mold face", "top half molding box"],
    correctAnswer: "top half molding box",
    question: "Cape in foundry practice refers to",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["four jaw chuck", "magnetic chuck", "collet chuck", "universal chuck"],
    correctAnswer: "universal chuck",
    question: "A kind of chuck, which should not be used where accuracy is required called",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["counter sinking", "reaming", "spot facing", "counter boring"],
    correctAnswer: "reaming",
    question: "The operation of finishing drilled hole to the correct size is known as",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["ductility", "hardness", "plasticity", "toughness"],
    correctAnswer: "plasticity",
    question: "A metal characteristic that absorbs extreme deformation without rupture is called:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["UNEF", "8-Thread Series", "UNC", "UNF"],
    correctAnswer: "UNC",
    question: "A kind of thread that is generally used.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["faster", "slower", "at a slower speed backwards", "at the same speed backwards"],
    correctAnswer: "slower",
    question: "When a lathe is put into back gear, it will go                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["have small flat areas on the surfaces", "be perfect", "be out of round", "A and C"],
    correctAnswer: "A and C",
    question: "When filling a piece of metal in a lathe if short quick strokes are used the finished piece will probably.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["plasticity", "toughness", "resilience", "creep"],
    correctAnswer: "resilience",
    question: "Ability of a material to absorb energy when deformed elastically and return to it when unloaded is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["2 flutes", "3 flutes", "1 flute", "4 flutes"],
    correctAnswer: "2 flutes",
    question: "A drill bit has",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["0.328", "0.823", "0.283", "0.832"],
    correctAnswer: "0.283",
    question: "Specific weight of steel in lbs/inches^3.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["collect chuck", "four jaw chuck", "two jaw chuck", "magnetic chuck"],
    correctAnswer: "magnetic chuck",
    question: "When large number of components are turned and parter off a bar the chuck generally used is the _______.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["10 to 13", "8 to 10", "18 to 20", "5 to 6"],
    correctAnswer: "8 to 10",
    question: "Cast Iron flywheels are commonly designated with a factor of safety of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["slide-filling", "milling-filling", "draw-filling", "flat-filling"],
    correctAnswer: "draw-filling",
    question: "Finishing off a piece of metal with a real smooth finish can be done by",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["conduit", "sheet metal under 18 gage", "any of the above", "small tubing"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "A hacksaw blade with 32 TPI is best suited for cutting                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["70Â°", "64Â°", "59Â°", "45Â°"],
    correctAnswer: "59Â°",
    question: "A correct cutting angle on a drill for ordinary work is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["speed greater than that when using a high speed drill", "speed less than that when using a high speed drill", "the same speed as that using a high speed steel", "none of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "speed less than that when using a high speed drill",
    question: "Carbon steel should be operated at",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["soluble oil", "kerosene", "dry", "soda water"],
    correctAnswer: "dry",
    question: "Cutting lubricants used in drilling, reaming and lapping of cast iron parts.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["brass", "thin wall tubing", "heavy", "cast iron"],
    correctAnswer: "thin wall tubing",
    question: "A hackaw blade with 34 teeth per inch should be used for cutting",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["double top rake", "less top rake", "any of these", "more top rake"],
    correctAnswer: "less top rake",
    question: "When cutting material in a lathe, the softer the material being cut, the tool bit should have",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Copper", "High carbon steel", "Low carbon steel", "Medium carbon steel"],
    correctAnswer: "Copper",
    question: "The mould for casting ferrous materials",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["give desired direction of the movement to the lathe carriage", "cut thread", "cut gears", "reducing spindle speed"], correctAnswer: "give desired direction of the movement to the lathe carriage",
    question: "The purpose of tumbler gears in lathe is to:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["broaching machine", "grinding machine", "lathe machine", "milling machine"],
    correctAnswer: "milling machine",
    question: "A machine tool used to produce a variety of surfaces by using a circular type cutter with multiple teeth.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["lathe", "shaper", "milling", "planer"],
    correctAnswer: "shaper",
    question: "A machine tool used principally to machine flat or plane surfaces with a single point cutting tool",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["taper bores", "screw thread", "cylindrical bores", "spherical holes"],
    correctAnswer: "cylindrical bores",
    question: "A plug gage is used to measure",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["coefficient of fluctuation", "coefficient of friction", "coefficient of restitution", "coefficient of velocity"],
    correctAnswer: "coefficient of restitution",
    question: "The ratio of relative viscosities colliding bodies after impact to their velocity before impact.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["inserting thermometer", "using an inside micrometer", "rotating and measuring the nearest permanent fitting", "inserting a feeler gage between coupling faces at varios points around the circumference"],
    correctAnswer: "inserting a feeler gage between coupling faces at varios points around the circumference",
    question: "The alignment of coupling faces can checked by                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["will only fit a solid frame hacksaw", "has the entire blade hardened", "has a flexible back and hared teeth", "has a hard back and flexible teeth"],
    correctAnswer: "has the entire blade hardened",
    question: "A hard hacksaw blade is one that",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["fine grains", "coarse grain", "round grains", "medium grains"],
    correctAnswer: "coarse grain",
    question: "Permeability, in relation to molding sands, is high for",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["planning", "boring", "turning", "chamfering"],
    correctAnswer: "chamfering",
    question: "Knurling is done to _______.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["a movable blade", "flexible ends", "only the teeth hardened", "only the back hardened"],
    correctAnswer: "only the teeth hardened",
    question: "A flexible hacksaw blade is one that has ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["dial indicator", "speedometer", "dial gage", "tachometer"],
    correctAnswer: "dial indicator",
    question: "It is used to true and align machine tools fixtures and works to test and inspect size trueness of finished work and compare measurements either heights or depths or many other measurements.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["30Â°", "60Â°", "120Â°", "110Â°"],
    correctAnswer: "110Â°",
    question: "The usual value of helix angle of a drill is:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["reaming", "planning", "turning", "shaping"],
    correctAnswer: "shaping",
    question: "A machining operation whereby the tool reciprocates and the feed is stationary.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["gloves on", "a pair of pulley", "a vise or clamp", "the hand"],
    correctAnswer: "a vise or clamp",
    question: "When using a drill press, the work should be held with                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["Charpy test", "Description test", "Izod test", "Rockwell test"],
    correctAnswer: "Rockwell test",
    question: "It is a machine used for testing of very thin steel or surface layers.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["bumps", "clogs", "flats", "pins"],
    correctAnswer: "pins",
    question: "Small piece of metal clogged between the teeth on a file are called",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["rubbed with emery cloth", "case hardened", "rubbed with crocus cloth", "stoned with oil stone"],
    correctAnswer: "stoned with oil stone",
    question: "After grinding the tool bit; the cutting edge should be",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["any of the above", "tungsten alloy steel", "tool steel", "high speed"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "Hacksaw blades are made of",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["long slow stroke", "short even stroke", "short fast stroke", "long fast stroke"],
    correctAnswer: "long slow stroke",
    question: "The best produce when filling a piece of metal in a lathe is to take _______",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["UNICEF", "BOT", "MIRDC", "DOST"],
    correctAnswer: "MIRDC",
    question: "An agency handling assistance to all foundry, machine shop and metallurgical plant operation.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["metal is poured into die cavity and after a predetermined time the mould is inverted to permit a part of main steel in molten state to flow out of cavity", "metal is forced into mould under high pressure", "cavity is filled with a precalculated quantity of metal and a core or plunger is inserted to force the metal into cavity", "molten metal is fed into the cavity in metallic mould by gravity"],
    correctAnswer: "cavity is filled with a precalculated quantity of metal and a core or plunger is inserted to force the metal into cavity",
    question: "In Carthias process",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["the teeth pointing backward", "the teeth facing forward", "the teeth facing in any direction ", "one end looser than the other"],
    correctAnswer: "the teeth facing forward",
    question: "The hacksaw blade should be placed in the frame with                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["reducing", "desizing", "upgrading", "upsetting"],
    correctAnswer: "upsetting",
    question: "In machine shop forging operation of lengthening a piece of stock while reducing the cross sectional area of work is called:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["85XX", "92XX", "87XX", "93XX"],
    correctAnswer: "92XX",
    question: "AISI numbering for silicon steel.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["turning", "shaping", "reaming", "milling"],
    correctAnswer: "milling",
    question: "A machining operation whereby the tool rotates and the feed is stationary",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["lathe machine", "shaper", "broaching machine", "planer"],
    correctAnswer: "broaching machine",
    question: "A cutting tool used to finish internal and external surfaces by the use of a cutter called broach, which has a series of cutting edges of teeth.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["knurling", "quenching", "indexing", "soldering"],
    correctAnswer: "knurling",
    question: "The process of checking or producing checkers on the surface of the piece by rolling checkered depressions in the surface",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["butt", "mandrel", "wobble", "mesh"],
    correctAnswer: "mandrel",
    question: "A tool when pressed into a finished hole in a piece of work, provides center on which the place may be turned otherwise machine called                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["solid iron", "cast iron", "aluminum", "any of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "A hacksaw blade with 10 teeth per inch is best suited for cutting",
    topic: "NA"
  },
]